A Guide to the Papers of Phi Beta Kappa, 1964-1986
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Phi Beta Kappa 1964-1986
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-23/22/1.871, RG-23/22/1.901
This collection consists of 2.5 feet (ca. 2000 items).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access to confidential records, including student grades and letters of recommendation, is restricted to sitting officers of Beta of Virginia, Phi Beta Kappa.
Acquisition Information
Collection RG-23/22/1.871 was an archival transfer from the chapter through Jon D. Mikalson, Classics Dept., 143 Cabell Hall, University of Virginia on 1987 August 12.
Collection RG-23/22/1.901 was a gift from Joseph Vaughn, 2109 Morris Road, Charlottesville, Va. 22903 on 1990 July 20.
Biographical/Historical Information
National academic honor society
Scope and Content Information
The papers contain correspondence and administrative files of the local chapter.
General correspondence files contain letters re chapter business including meetings, prizes, local events, membership acceptances and refusals, and notices from the national council. Administrative files contain annual reports, constitution and by laws, and correspondence and other material re awards, visiting scholars, special activities and membership lists. There is also correspondence re the nomination, election and initiation of candidates.
A lecture, Ivory towers in a secular world by [C. Vann?] Woodward completes the collection.
Contents List
- I: Correspondence
  - Correspondence--General 1964-1980, 10 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--General 1981-1985, 7 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence--General 1986 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence--Acceptance Letters 1972, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence--Form Letters 1971-1985 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence--Letters to Out-of-Towners 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence--Passover Letter to Rabbi Krinsky 1975 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence--President to Members 1976-1981 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence--Refusals 1972-1973 (Box 3)
- II: Administrative Records
  - Administrative--Annual Reports 1978-1981 (Box 3)
  - Administrative--Bylaws 1977 (Box 3)
  - Administrative--Constitution 1968-1983 (Box 3)
  - Administrative--Founder's Day 1974 (Box 3)
  - Administrative--Hereford Inauguration 1974 (Box 3)
  - Administrative--Information n.d. (Box 3)
  - Administrative--Pass-Fail Study Committee 1969 (Box 3)
  - Administrative--President's Charge to Electorate 1978-1980 (Box 3)
  - Administrative--Programs 1974-1985 (Box 3)
  - Administrative--Secretary's Information 1970-1984 (Box 3)
  - Administrative--Song Sheets n.d. (Box 3)
- III: Awards and Prizes
  - Awards and Prizes 1972-1981, 5 folders (Box 4)
- IV: Visiting Scholars
  - Visiting Scholars--General 1971-1973 (Box 4)
  - Visiting Scholars--Rosen, Charles 1977 (Box 4)
  - Visiting Scholars--Eccles, Sir John 1977 (Box 4)
  - Visiting Scholars--Miller, J. Hillis 1978 (Box 4)
  - Visiting Scholars--Casteen, John 1978-1981 (Box 4)
- V: Membership
  - Membership--List 1972-1981, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Membership--Mailing List 1981 (Box 4)
  - Membership--List of Degree Candidates 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Membership--Master List 1982 (Box 4)
  - Membership--Mailing List 1985 (Box 4)
  - Membership--List of Chapters n.d. (Box 4)
  - Membership--Candidates 1965-1972, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Membership--Candidates 1973-1985, 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Membership--Election 1970-1981, 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Membership--Initiation and Banquet 1970-1981, 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Membership--Initiation and Banquet 1982-1984, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Membership--Initiation In Absentia 1977-1984, 6 folders (Box 6)
  - Membership--Key Problems 1972-1974 (Box 6)
  - Membership--Key Order Forms 1978-1986, 4 folders (Box 6)
- VI: Miscellaneous
  - TMs--"Ivory Towers in a Secular World" 1977 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous [RG-23/22/1.901] [1953-1976] (Box 6)
  - Correspondence--General 1978-1984 (Box 7)
    Restricted Material
  - Administrative n.d. (Box 7)
  - Departmental Recommendations 1972-1973 (Box 7)
  - Honorary & Alum. Comm.--Recommendations 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Honors & Graduate Students--Recommendations 1974 (Box 7)
  - Membership Candidates 1965-1985 (Box 7)
  - Membership Elections 1970-1981 (Box 7)